There's just no way I can beat him I'm just I'm just hoping that I can stop a few of his spikes
There's just no way I can stop a few of his spikes
Wall梡根の輝きが迷える共の明日を不 anlam志
夢中仕立たように背負い切れて
imeおいiov Tu Janателяに光あれ
That jerk baited Ushuaka into hitting right where he wanted him.
He pretended there was a clear opening for him and then took it away last second.
Bet that four-eyed douche thinks he's smart.
Well, he did lose his set because of him.
Come to think of it, should I be scared that Coach hasn't raged at us for it yet?
Shirabu.
Yes?
Judging by the look on your face, I can tell you already know.
You all right there, Shirabu?
You know, if this had been a practice match, you would have slapped me.
You think so?
It's not like your set was the only screw-up of the game.
This stuff happens to the best of us.
This wasn't just a simple mistake.
Shirabu!
Oh.
Let's start it off right.
Cover it.
Shake it off! Set's just starting.
Yeah!
Sure, Torizawa.
Was not shaken up from that last set.
Yeah.
Yeah!
I can tell that their setter isn't letting the last round get him down.
If anything, he's more focused now.
I have to hand it to them.
That attack was praiseworthy.
I always get a bit awestruck when someone performs at the top of their game.
But...
All right!
Sure, your tosses have been stellar all game.
Thanks.
Back then, our team was pretty strong.
But in the end, it would often come down to these two schools duking it out for the championship.
Kitagawa first made up for the lack of size with their strategies using their incredible speed and skill combinations.
That refinement is something we could have tried to mimic.
And from my perspective as a setter, Mikawa came across as a monster out there.
However, I found myself pushing aside things like skilled teamwork and group attacks.
I became captivated with height and power.
These attributes were the embodiment of the perfect playstyle for me.
The kind of style where even if you play poorly, you can pull off a clutch win with just one open toss.
The kind of style where this setter doesn't need to control the whole game.
I'm gonna go to Shira Torizawa.
Hmm? What?
I'm going to play with the strongest players.
So I can play at that level.
This was the epitome of volleyball to me.
I'll become the setter that stands up the least.
Damn it!
Focus! We'll get next!
Hey, are you okay, Nishinoya?
There's no getting around that height is a huge advantage in life.
And right now, Ushiwaka has that huge advantage over all of us on the team.
But a Libro doesn't give a crap about that.
The only one who's equal to him would be me.
I assume since you move so quickly, that you'd be good at blocks and receives, too.
Since I outclass you in pure height, you think your clumsy technique will make up for it?
Clumsy, inept, unrefined, oafish, blunderous.
Got it?
Got it!
Hey! Quit screwing around!
You know, you and Ushiwaka have more in common than you realize.
Huh?
You really think so?
Well, I don't see myself quite at his level, but I could see how you'd compare us.
That's not how I meant it, you big dummy!
Shira Torizawa!
Come take a breather!
So now you've seen it up close and personal.
You've seen firsthand what it's like to take on a team like Shira Torizawa.
And what you are doing is working, so stick with it.
However, we're still at a major disadvantage, so don't let yourselves get too cocky.
I need to emphasize that we need to keep the blocking together and stay out of the receiver's way.
And don't you ever forget, our true power is teamwork, playing together.
That's how we win!
Yes, sir!
Hey, Asahi.
Huh?
Come on, give us a nice serve!
I'm so in the zone right now.
I'll get us one right here!
That's out!
Ah, damn it!
Thanks, dude!
Rail!
Nice receive!
From what I've observed, Ushiwaka has only a handful of patterns.
He spikes down, he spikes through.
And when we're lucky, we'll get a one-touch.
Or...
So if Ushiwaka tries to come in for one of his quick attacks from the right side, he will most likely attempt a cross-court spike.
We can shut him out together.
With a two-man block!
We won't have the same advantages as a three-man block, obviously.
But while we are distracting him, it'll give our team's guardian a clear vision of follow-up.
There's only one person on the court who's Ushiwaka's equal.
Me.
I absolutely will not let him win!
Nice receive!
Hey, dumbass!
Do I need to call Child Protective Services?
You're standing around like a lost kid at the mall!
Sorry!
Coach seems calmer this game, but still has it out for me.
Do you know why he always gets the maddest with you, Goshki?
Because I suck, right?
Actually, it's because he expects the most from you.
Huh?
Bring it on!
Good grief. What a little lunkhead.
I just told him the honest truth.
You're so slow, Blondie.
Blocking is all about reading and intuition.
No, blocking is a system.
Hinata!
Goshki!
Bet this bastard tries to go for a super shark straight again.
Nice!
Hinata's quick with the follow-up!
How did he find an opening?
Huh?
What?
He squeezed the ball through there?
That was a fluke shot, huh?
Fluke?
Don't be absurd.
Don't you know you can expect these miracle plays?
From aces like me?
Oh, don't even.
You're not fooling anybody.
So, as amazing as that last play was, we'll just have to kick things up and take the points back in the even more badass way.
Yeah!
Nice to see it!
Come on!
Use our numbers to our advantage!
Go for the synchronized attack!
Great.
Here comes that damn attack again.
But wait.
They stopped the synchronized attack?
How did that happen?
No.
Go for the synchronized attack!
The Funnee Team!
Go for the ray警!
No.
Go for the synchronized attack!
Go for theansing!
You won't need my incredible energy in the hasilvy!
Go for the fruit!
Go for the national!
Go for the finale!
Go for the night!
Go for theки!
Go for the winks!
Bang deber!
Go for theкими!
Twitter!
Cl contingent!
Clости!
Their number 12 is sharp.
I think he was able to determine that the entire right side was out of the picture on that play.
And he figured it out by looking at Daichi's position alone.
It's not that a follow-up by Daichi would be impossible or anything,
but I'd say it would be more that the odds were improbable.
If only you guys took the game this seriously a few years back.
Oh, hello, sir!
At ease, fellas.
Although I do clearly remember, you two always going for the ball without thinking.
We were doing the best we could, sir.
That Dusty Fossil is the old coach.
He's Yuka's grandpa.
There we go.
I see Washijo's still kicking and has assembled yet another solid lineup.
They're a mess.
If Karasano hadn't tried to attack all at once,
they might have had some people left to follow up that block.
I have to agree.
Our play styles are completely different.
But we both like to steal points by force.
I guess we aren't so different after all.
Yes!
This is turning into a battle of philosophies.
It's just like the old days going against Yukai.
These two groups of high schoolers are a good way to settle our score.
It'll determine which of our methods is the strongest.
Lay down a nice one, Daishi!
If Ushiwaka's not serving or receiving,
we should keep everything confined to the left side.
We got it!
Nice receive, Rayon!
We force the action.
Force Ushiwaka to attack.
Okay, now!
I've seen Tsukishima irritated plenty of times,
but this might be the first time I've seen him this frustrated.
Yeah!
Good! It's offline!
On my mark!
And now!
If Ushiwaka gets a perfect set and blasts it through our defense,
there's not much we can do.
So we'll need to try and stop sets from getting to him.
We'll have center defense step back here
so we can have two or more blockers on him at all times.
The more the better.
Stay on his ass!
Oh, so just like Inoshita did in our match against Wakuno.
Exactly.
And since Tsukishima is doing an exceptional job
holding his own as our center blocker,
it's worth trying this.
Only one step back.
But it's an important one.
Even though Tanaka and Hinata have quick reaction times,
we can't let the responsibility of picking up these shots fall on them.
Daishi! Got it!
Tanaka, get the last hit!
Cover the back!
I know where you're going.
What the hell?
He stopped it!
It's your miracle boy!
Stop!
Don't!
Pretend-o!
Damn it!
Was he seriously able to guess that spike
without knowing exactly where it was coming from?
Nice.
Good job stopping that.
Mm-hmm.
Ha!
I caught him not paying attention to the blockers from his stance.
Besides, spikers are predictable creatures.
They always glance at the direction they're about to shoot.
So that's how he decides which way to go.
I guess Karasuno's number five's body language said he was planning on hitting it there all along.
Nintendo picked up on him.
Relax.
It's fine.
That was a pretty amazing block we just witnessed.
Shut your face!
Not too shabby.
They're pulling off these high-level moves without trying to outthink themselves.
But their opponents are called champions for a reason.
They'll need to pull out all the stops if they are going to win.
Give us a nice serve, Ushiwaka!
Sorry!
What the heck just happened?
How in the hell is that Ushiwaka guy even a real person?
Do it again!
Cover that!
I'm not going to allow them to extend this lead anymore!
Wait.
That's a low block.
Yeah!
All yours, man!
Hey.
How about you start scoring some points while you're up in front?
We could kind of use...
I know!
Oh, hey.
Come to think of it.
Didn't Ushiwaka have some words with Hinata in between the sets?
Oh.
Yeah.
Shrimps are only for eating, not for playing volleyball.
That's what he said.
Seriously?
That wasn't just as complex?
That's exactly what I thought also.
But that seems to be exactly what he meant.
Hinata's probably stewing on the inside right now.
You're not really one to talk.
If you think about it.
Hinata wouldn't be here if he was the type to get his spirit broken over a few insults.
That's the cap.
Good.
Sorry about that.
It's short.
Rayon!
Since I outclassed you in pure height, you think your clumsy technique will make up for it?
Damn it.
Tall guys don't know how easy they've got it.
It makes me jealous, but...
He's getting ready to block, but he's running in like...
He's about to spike.
That approaching run...
Makes him look like he has weanies.
He stopped it!
I might envy your height...
But I can use mine to my advantage as well.
How do you like that?
Karasuno got a break.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Did my vision just fail me, or did that little number 10 fella finally get a decent block?
Well, I don't know.
Number 10 plays kind of erratic, so I think it was probably a fluke.
Maybe you should go sit up there with Mr. Grumpy Pants, Mr. Early Critical.
True.
But if it's not a fluke, this game's about to change.
Big time.
Nishinoya.
Hinata to the rescue!
He should just do that every time!
No, no, no!
He can't do the same thing every time, and besides that, won't counter fast attacks!
And it would also do a number on his stamina.
Middle blockers jump around the most as it is.
Plus, Hinata is working overtime.
Jumping at full power to compensate for his height.
Funny that's coming from you, a guy who would invent new ways to slack off during a game.
Oh, you know it!
Can't complain if you were actually good while playing lazy.
Get it, Rayon!
One more time!
I knew that was gonna happen.
My God, I'm sorry!
It's okay.
Think about where you're going, you tiny dumbass!
Hinata, I've got a message from Coach.
Forget what you know about jumping, let's try something new.
Instead of jumping up, try doing a sideways sweep.
So you guys can...
Support his jump from the sides!
Got it!
My timing's still off!
I hope I can nail this!
Hit it right back!
Kill it!
If you could play a good game of volleyball while being lazy,
cat gripe,
but a small fry over there
has no choice but to jump.
Nice kill, Hinata!
I didn't expect to see you.
I thought you said you weren't coming
since this game's outcome would piss you off no matter who won.
I might have said something like that,
but I didn't come here to watch someone win.
I came to watch someone lose.
Such a piece of crap.
I can't wallow in self-pity all day.
So I see Karasuno's number 10
is doing laps around the court as usual.
The little guy is definitely a monster.
I must say I feel sorry for anyone
who has to play with him.
It's me!
Tanaka!
Yeah!
Let him have it, Suki!
The jump's peak!
The jump's...
peak!
Front!
Left side!
One touch!
Chance ball!
Pushybaka!
Come on, Hinata!
I'll be here.
Support!
It's a one touch!
I got it!
Don't fade on me, Hinata!
Why don't you shut up?
He's really running all the way to the other side?
Oh, crap.
I got it!
Yeah!
Break support, Tanaka!
Well done!
An upperclassman, his only job is to help those younger than he!
Nice haiku!
It's a freak!
Hinata!
Nice one touch!
Karasuna's really reckless.
First that sloppy, synchronized attack, and now this?
Let them wear themselves down.
They might have these tricky techniques and combinations,
but our sheer power will win in the end.
If a player's height and physical ability
were the only determining factor to win a game,
then this match would have been settled a long time ago.
But because there's so much more to the game,
it makes this match-up all the more interesting.
Thank you.
You're clicking your tongue more than usual, Tsukishima.
You sound like a clock.
A clock?
What the hell does a clock have to do with volleyball?
Just focus on the match, you two.
Next Haikyuu, the chemical changes of meeting.